<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<automorphismGroups>
  <problem tex="Let $\Omega$ be a region. Recall an automorphism of $\Omega$ is a biholomorphism from $\Omega$ to $\Omega$. The set of automorphisms forms a group under composition, currently we only care because we like the term &quot;automorphism group of $\Omega$.&quot;&#xA;We say the automorphism group of $\Omega$ is transitive if for each $x,y\in\Omega$ there is an automorphism $\phi_{x,y}$ such that $\phi_{x,y}(x)=y$. We say the automorphism group is spin-transitive if for all $x,y\in\Omega$ and $\lambda\in\mathbb{C}^*$, there is an automorphism $\phi_{x,y}^\lambda$ such that $\phi_{x,y}^\lambda(x)=y$ and&#xA;\[\frac{\left(\phi_{x,y}^\lambda\right)'(x)}{\lambda}&gt;0.\]&#xA;That is, the derivative at $x$ points in the same direction as $\lambda$. Note that the derivative of an automorphism cannot vanish.&#xA;Let $\Omega$ be a simply connected region. Prove the automorphism group of $\Omega$ is spin transitive. What about if $\Omega$ is the annulus $A=1&lt;|z|&lt;2$?">
    <instructors>
      <e/>
    </instructors>
    <topics>
      <MobiusTransformation/>
      <RiemannMapping/>
      <Harmonic/>
      <PointSetTopology/>
      <MaximumPrinciple/>
    </topics>
  </problem>
  <solution tex="If $\Omega$ is a simply connected region, then either $\Omega=\mathbb{C}$ or not. In the first case, affine linear maps provide enough automorphisms of $\Omega$ to prove the result. Concretely, $\phi_{x,y}^\lambda(z)=\lambda(z-x)+y$. If $\Omega\neq\mathbb{C}$ then $\Omega$ is biholomorphic to $\mathbb{D}$ by the Riemann mapping theorem. Mobius transformations combined with rotations provide enough automorphisms of the disc to conclude that the automorphism group of the disc is spin-transitive, and this property is preserved under biholomorphism. We can fix a biholomorphism from $\Omega$ to $\mathbb{D}$, trace out the desired behavior in $\mathbb{D}$, obtain that behavior with an automorphism of the disc, and then pull it back to $\Omega$ via the biholomorphism. We omit the details at present.&#xA;For the annulus, the automorphism group is much smaller. We presume that we know any automorphism of $A$ extends continuously to the boundary (I'm still not quite sure how this works, see Kellogg's theorem), whence it must take the boundary to the boundary. Moreover it either exchanges the two circles or not. If the circles were exchanged we can compose with $\frac{1}{2z}$ to unexchange the circles, so we investigate now all automorphisms of $A$ which do not exchange the boundary circles.&#xA;Suppose $\phi:A\to A$ is an automorphism which does not exchange the two boundary circles. Then the function $\frac{\phi(z)}{z}:A\to\mathbb{C}$ is holomorphic. Moreover, for all $z\in\partial A$,&#xA;\[\left|\frac{\phi(z)}{z}\right|=\frac{|\phi(z)|}{|z|}=1\]&#xA;precisely because the circles are not exchanged. By the maximum principle applied to the real and imaginary parts of $\frac{\phi(z)}{z}$, this function must be constant because it is constant on the boundary. Thus $\phi(z)=\lambda z$ with $|\lambda|=1$, so $\phi$ is just a rotation.&#xA;We conclude by recognizing that we have shown any automorphism of $A$ is either a rotation or $\frac{1}{2z}$ followed by a rotation. This is too restrictive for the automorphism group to be transitive, we can see this because any automorphism fixes the circle $|z|=\frac{\sqrt{2}}{2}$. Clearly rotations fix this circle, and $\frac{1}{2z}$ fixes this circle as well. Thus $\frac{\sqrt{2}}{2}$ can never be sent to $\frac{3}{2}$ via an automorphism of $A$, so the automorphism group is not transitive."/>
</automorphismGroups>